Guide to the Leopold Haimson papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Leopold Haimson Papers,
1890s-1999
Haimson, Leopold H. 1927-
88 linear ft. (164 document boxes, 4 flat boxes; 2 record storage boxes).
Columbia University. Rare Book & Manuscript Library. Bakhmeteff Archive Butler Library, 6th Fl. East, 535 West 114th St., New York, NY. 10027
6909647
The papers comprise correspondence, documents, institutional files, writings, lectures, memoirs, research notes, photographs, third party materials, printed materials, periodicals, microfilms, audio material, and digital files accrued by historian and professor emeritus of Columbia University, Leopold H. Haimson, during his professional life.
Biographical Note
Leopold Henri Haimson is a historian and professor emeritus of Columbia University, where he worked since 1965 as a professor of Russian history and a member of the Harriman Institute for Advanced Study of Eurasia.
Haimson was born in Brussels, Belgium on April 28, 1927 in a family of immigrants from Russia. He resided there up to the age of 13, when the German invasion in 1940 prompted his family to escape, first to unoccupied France, and eventually to the United States. He received his Bachelor of Arts degree in history and philosophy from Harvard University in 1945 and his PhD in history and social relations there in 1952. His professional background includes his work as a research associate at Columbia University (1948-1949, 1950-1952), American Museum of Natural History and Center for International Studies (1948-1949, 1951-1952); a visiting research scholar at Princeton University (1952-1953); a lecturer in the Russian Regional Program and the Department of History at Harvard University (1955-1956); an assistant professor and then a professor of Russian History at University of Chicago (1956-1966). From 1960 to 1965, Leopold Haimson served as the director of the Inter-University Project on the History of the Menshevik Movement. In 1964-1965, he was a research associate at Hoover Institute and a visiting scholar at the Center for Advanced Studies in the Behavioral Sciences. He became a professor in the Department of History and the Russian Institute at Columbia University in 1966
A distinguishing feature of Haimson's career has been his role as the organizer of collaborative research projects that have brought together scholars from different disciplines and different academic cultures, especially those of the United States, France, and Russia. Starting in 1982, in addition to his work for the Inter-University Project on the History of the Menshevik Movement, he was a director of the International Project in Comparative Labor History, based at the Maison des Sciences de l'Homme (Paris), for almost two decades. He also served as co-chairman of the International Commission for Joint Projects in Modern Russian History. Starting in the 1960s, he became involved in Soviet academic life. His efforts to develop contacts between Soviet and American specialists in Russian history resulted in an extensive scholar exchange program between the Soviet Union and the United States. He helped organize a regular series of workshops in the form of international colloquia devoted to discussions of various historical problems in a comparative perspective that brought together American, European, and Russian scholars. He was also a visiting lecturer at Moscow University, at the Institute of History, and at the European University in St. Petersburg.
Haimson's scholarly interests include political culture, social and quantitative history, the dynamics of strike movements in a comparative perspective, as well as cultural anthropology and the application of its concepts and methodology to studies of the Soviet Union. Since the publication of his influential "The Russian Marxists and the Origins of Bolshevism" in 1955, Leopold Haimson has published many books and articles and edited volumes on Russian political, social, and intellectual life in late imperial and revolutionary Russia in English, French, and Russian
Scope and Content
The bulk of the collection consists of Leopold H.Haimson correspondence (including correspondence with Isaiah Berlin, letters from Joseph Brodsky, and correspondence with prominent historians and scholars), writings by Haimson and other authors, manuscripts, research and archival materials from Soviet archives and libraries, printed materials, and institutional documents from the History Department of Columbia University, the Harriman Institute, and the History Department of the University of Chicago. There are also documents, memoirs, microfilms, audio materials, digital files, and photographs.
The collection documents the variety of Leopold Haimson's professional activity as a professor of Russian history, scholar, editor, conductor of various collaborative projects, organizer of and participant in numerous colloquia and conferences, faculty member at the University of Chicago and Columbia University, and one of the key figure in the development of Soviet-American academic relationships in his field.
It ought to be specially noted that Haimson Papers include extensive files on the history of Menshevism - a collection of materials known as the Archive on the History of Menshevism. The establishment of this archive was one of the main goals of the Inter-University Project on the History of the Menshevik Movement. It contains extensive collection of documents and newspapers of the Menshevik Party, Mensheviks' memoirs and case studies, correspondence, records and transcripts of interviews conducted by associates of the Project with survivors of the Party, transcripts of seminar discussions of various of the Project studies, biographical and bibliographical data, periodicals, and editorial materials of the "Sotsialisticheskii vestnik".
There are also research materials on the late imperial Russian social history, including Haimson's extensive collection of microfilms, photocopied newspapers, provincial census reports, rare journals, bibliographic files, and his own data files. The collection also contains Haimson's professional papers, which include correspondence as well as materials from his many trips to Russia, beginning in 1956, and which are a great source of information about the academic life of the 1950s and 1960s. In addition, there are institutional materials relating to the history of the Harriman Institute and to Soviet/Russian studies in general. Among other materials, included here are institutional records and correspondence of a broad sort.
Audio materials, oversize items, and digital files were removed from their original location and organized in series based on their format. References are provided.
Some correspondence and printed materials remain with materials to which they relate, and can be found in various series. References are provided.
Microfilms and periodicals and serial publications from the collection are in a process of been cataloged by individual title, as of the February 2009.
Leopold Haimson's rich collection of microfilms contains research materials, such as books and periodicals, and archival documents on Russian social history from various archives and libraries. It also includes microfilms belonging to the Menshevik project, which contain a variety of materials related to the history of the Menshevik movement: periodicals, books, archival materials from Soviet archives and libraries. Upon completion of the cataloging process, microfilms from Leopold Haimson's collection will be available in the Microform Reading Room. For the comprehensive list of microfilms see Appendix 2 in the paper copy of the finding aid.
There is some number of microfilm reels with unidentified materials thus they can not be cataloged. These microfilms are part of the Series X: Research and Reference Materials.
Leopold Haimson's collection of periodical and serial publications contains newspapers, magazines, census reports, bulletins, statistical data mostly of the period of late 19th-beginning of 20th centuries. It also includes periodicals belonging to the Menshevik project, such as Menshevik publications, newspapers, and magazines, which were collected in various available formats as originals, photocopies, and microfilms. Originals and photocopies are cataloged for the SEEC collection (Soviet and East European Collection of printed materials in the Bakhmeteff archive) and will be available in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library upon completion of the cataloging process. Periodicals preserved on microfilms will be available in the Microform Reading Room. For the comprehensive list of periodicals see Appendix 1 in the paper copy of the finding aid.
There are cross-references provided throughout the finding aid. When the cross-reference refers to another item within the same series, the reference includes the specific name or title and box and folder number (this also applies to the references within same subseries and sub-subseries). If the cross-reference is to an item in another series, the reference includes the series number, series name, folder title, and box and folder numbers (this also applies to the references to items in another subseries and sub-subseries).
Arrangement
In sixteen series:
Series I: Correspondence, 1950s-1990s
Series II: Writings, 1951-1994
Series III: Menshevik Project, 1890s-1977 (Inter-University Project on the History of Menshevik Movement)
Series IV: Strikes Project, 1980s
Series V: Seminars, 1948-1983
Series VI: Colloquia and Conferences, 1975-1991
Series VII: Editorial Activity, 1964-1974
Series VIII: Institutional Files, 1956-1990s
Series IX: Russian Files, 1957-1998
Series X: Research and Reference Materials, 1900s-1994
Series XI: Writings by Others, 1934-1990s
Series XII: CVs and Photographs, 1960s-1990s
Series XIII: Maps, 1900s
Series XIV: Audio Materials, 1960s
Series XV: Digital Files
Series XVI: Oversize Materials, 1920-1969
Subjects
Columbia University.; Harriman Institute.; Inter-university Project on the History of the Menshevik Movement.; Rossiiskaia sotsial-demokraticheskaia rabochaia partiia.; Rossiiskaia sotsial-demokraticheskaia rabochaia partiia--Bibliography.; Rossiiskaia sotsial-demokraticheskaia rabochaia partiia--History.; University of Chicago.; Aldanov, Mark Aleksandrovich, 1886-1957.; Aleksandrova, Vera, 1895-1966.; Aronson, Gregor, 1887-1968.; Balabanova, A. V.; Berlin, Isaiah, 1909-1997.; Brodsky, Joseph, 1940-1996.; Dalin, David G.; Dallin, Alexander, 1924-2000.; Damanskaia, A. (Avgusta), b. 1885; Dan, Lidiia.; Denicke, George.; Dvinov, Boris L'vovich--Manuscripts.; Galili y Garcia, Ziva.; Gershun, Boris L'vovich, 1870-1954.; Kuskova, Ekaterina.; Martov, L., 1873-1923.; Nicolaevsky, Boris I., 1887-1966.; Raeff, Marc.; Robinson, Geroid Tanquary, 1892-1971.; Rudol'f, V. V. (Vladimir Vasil'evich).; Schwarz, Solomon M.; Tsereteli, I. G. (Iraklii Georgievich), 1881-1959.; Vakar, Gertruda, 1904-1973.; Valentinov, N. (Nikolai), 1879-1964.; Veidle, V., 1895-1979.; Voloshin, Aleksandr.; Wortman, Richard.; Woytinsky, Wladimir S., 1885-1960.; Zamiatina, L. N. (Liudmila Nikolaevna), 1883-1965.; Zavalishin, Viacheslav.; Zhordania, Noe Nikolozisze, ca. 1868-1953.; Russia--History.; Russia--History--February Revolution, 1917.; Russia--History--Revolution, 1905-1907.; Russia--Periodicals.; Russia--Politics and government--1894-1917.; Russia--Maps.; Soviet Union--History--20th century; Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921; United States--Foreign relations--Soviet Union.; Biography; Labor movement--Europe.; Labor movement--Russia.; Memoirs and biographies.; Mensheviks.; Mensheviks--Georgia (Republic).; Mensheviks--Periodicals.; Revolutionaries--Russia--Biography.; Revolutionaries--Russia--Correspondence.; Revolutionaries--Soviet Union.; Revolutionaries--Soviet Union--Biography.; Russian-Americans.; Russian Studies--United States.; Socialism--Georgia (Republic).; Socialism--Russia--History--20th century.; Socialism--Russia--Periodicals.; Socialism--Soviet Union--History.; Strikes and lockouts--Europe--History.; Strikes and lockouts--Russia--History; Working class--Soviet Union--Bibliography.; Working class--Soviet Union.; Working class--Russia--Political activity--History--20th century.; Autobiographies; Correspondence
Access Restrictions
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
Gift Leopold Haimson May 2001 accn number
- Series I: Correspondence,1950s-1990s
  The series consists of Haimson's professional correspondence with various people and organizations, with related materials, such as articles, CVs, drafts, fellowship and scholarship applications. Organized into four subseries. More correspondence with people and organizations on particular subjects can be found in other series of the collection
  - Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Prominent Figures, 1960-1976
    Contains Haimson’s correspondence with Isaiah Berlin and Joseph Brodsky. Arranged alphabetically. More letters by prominent people, such as Mark Aldanov, Avgusta Damanskaia, Boris Gershun, Ekaterina Kuskova, Boris Nikolaevskii, Vladimir Rudol'f, Nikolai Valentinov, Vladimir Veidle, Aleksandr Voloshin, Liudmila Zamiatina, Viacheslav Zavalishin, and others addressed to various people, see: Series III: Menshevik Project-- Subseries III.2: Mensheviks' personal files.
    - Berlin, Isaiah, Oxford, 1960-1976, (1 autograph letter signed, 2 typed letters signed, with 2 carbon replies) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Brodsky, Joseph, no place, undated, (1 autograph note signed) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Subseries I.2: General Correspondence, 1959-1997
    Comprises Haimson’s correspondence with individuals, mostly his colleagues and students, and organizations. Arranged alphabetically by correspondent, then chronologically. Some files include related materials, such as writings, notes, printed materials, clippings, documents. Unidentified correspondence is at the end of the subseries.
    - Alef, Gustave, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Allworth, Edward, 1971, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Ascher, Abraham, 1966-1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Avrich, Paul, 1969-1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Bailes, Kendall, 1966-1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      (including materials of the conference "Industrialization and change in the USSR")
    - Bennigsen, Alexandre, 1970-1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Bennigsen, Elizabeth, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Bennigsen, Fanny, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Bennigsen, Helene, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Berk, Stephen, 1966-1983 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Berliner, Joseph, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Bezza, Bruno, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Black, Cyril, 1963-1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Bo, Jiuseppe del: see Fondazione Giaingiacomo Feltrinelli
    - Bociurkiw, Bohdan, 1959-1961 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Bohachevsky-Chomiak, Martha, 1967-1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Boll, Friedhelm, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Bonnain-Noerdijk, Rolande: see Tschistaganow
    - Bonnell, Victoria, 1967-1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Bordogna, Lorenzo, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Brainerd, Michael, 1968-1977 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Broido, Vera, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Brown, Truesdell: see University of California
    - Burgess, Keith, 1984, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Bushkovich, Paul, 1971-1974 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Calderwood, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Carmichael, Joel, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Chase, William, 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Cherniavskii, Michael (aka Cherniavsky), 1960-1973, (Cherniavskii's professional correspondence, documents, photographs, obituaries, material of commemoration meeting)
      - Correspondence, 1960-1973, (with related materials) (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
      - Obituaries, 1973, (with related correspondence) (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Commemoration meeting, 1974, (correspondence, papers) (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Photographs (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Chistoganov, Lilia: see Tschistaganow
    - Clive, Geoffrey, 1967-1972 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Confino, Michel, 1969-1984 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Cornell University, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Cronin, James, 1976-1987 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Cross, Robert: see Series VIII: Intstitutional Files--Subseries VIII.2: Columbia Univesity Files--History Department (Box 94, Folders 13-15 and Box 95, Folders 1-4)
    - Crummy, Robert, 1959-1974 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Dallin, Alexander, 1959-1988 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      (See also: Series III: Menshevik project--Subseries III.1: Project records--Sub-series III.1.4: Grant Files, Box 18, Folders 16 and 18)
    - Davenport, William: see Series VIII: Intstitutional Files--Subseries VIII.2: Columbia Univesity Files--Reid Hall (Box 99, Folder 11)
    - Dean, Craig, 1970-1975 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Dickerson, Connie, 1973-1979 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Doctorow, Gilbert, 1968-1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Domansky, Elizabeth, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Dumont, Marianne, 1982-1988 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Economakis, Evel, 1984-1988 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Edelman, Robert, 1968-1979 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Elwood, Ralph, 1963-1969 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Emmons, Terence, 1971-1980 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Engel, Barbara, 1971-1982 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Engelstein, Laura, 1976-1988 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Erlich, Alexander, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Field, Daniel, 1970-1989 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Fisch, Jerry, 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Fisch, Mary (nee Mary Nelson), 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      (See also her correspondence of 1959-1969 with L.Haimson and other people: Series III: Menshevik project--Subseries III.1: Project records--Sub-subseries III.1.1: Correspondence--Chronological, Box 14, Folders 1-7)
    - Fisher, Ralph, 1965-1970 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Fisher, Raymond: see University of California
    - Fondazione Giangiacomo Feltrinelli, 1960-1989 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Freeze, Gregory, 1968-1988 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Galai, Shmuel, 1970-1973 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Galili y Garcia, Ziva, 1973-1985, (correspondence with her and about her, CV, grant applications, etc) (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Gershuni, Iakov, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Gerstein, George and Linda, 1970-1972, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Getty, J.Arch, 1980-1984 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Geyer, D., 1973 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Glatzer, Bernice: see Rosenthal, Bernice
    - Glickman, Rose, 1960-1976 (Box 3, Folder 3-4)
    - Goldberg, David and Nadine, 1960-1971 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Goldstein, Edward, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Gottschalk, Fruma, 1961-1967 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Graham, Loren, 1970-1989 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Greene, Nathanael, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Grigorian, Vartan, 1967-1988 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Grimsted, Patricia, 1970-1980 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Groh, Dieter, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Gutman, Herbert, 1974-1980 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Halliwel, Steven, 1967-1977 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      (Students for a Democratic Society)
    - Halperin, Charles, 1971-1980 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Heller, Clemens, 1965-1984 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      (See also his letters of 1962-1964 Series III: Menshevik project--Subseries III.1: Project record--Sub-subseries III.1.1: Correspondence--General--Ecole Pratique des Hautes Etudes, Box 15, Folder 1, and also other files of Menshevik project correspondence)
    - Hellie, Richard, 1960-1987 (Box 3, Folder 11-12)
    - Heuman, Susan, 1969-1977 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Hildermeier, Manfred, 1988-1991 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Hobsbaum, Eric, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Hoffman, David, 1985-1993 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Hogan, Heather, 1980-1988 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Hosking, Jeoffrey, 1967-1986 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Hutchinson, John F., 1966-1970 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Istituto Giangiacomo Feltrinelli: see Fondazione Giangiacomo Feltrinelli
    - Jakobson, Mikhail, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Jelin, Arnold, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Johnson, Mark, 1988-1997 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Johnson, R., 1975 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Johnson, Walter, 1960-1964see Series VIII: Institutional Files--Subseries VIII.1: Chicago University files--History department--General correspondence (Box 89, Folder 6)
    - Juviler, Peter, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      (Barnard College)
    - Kaelble, Hartmut, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Kagan-Kans, Eva, 1966-1972 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Kahan, Arcadius, 1960-1974 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Kaminski, Andrzej, 1970-1988 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Kaplan, Herbert, 1967-1970 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Karlin, Jules, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Kazarinov, Samantha, 1970-1977 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Kenan, Edward, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Kerblay, Basile,1984 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Kimberling, Elise, 1979-1983 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - King, Jere: see University of California
    - Kline, George, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Koenker, Diane, 1976-1987 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Kolesnichenko, Diana, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Krieger, Leonard, 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - La Belle, Dale, 1960-1976 (Box 4, Folder 6-9)
    - Lagrange, Hugues, 1983-1988 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Lelchuk, Alan, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Levin, Alfred, 1968-1970 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Lewin, Moshe, 1973-1988 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Liber, George, 1980-1985 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Lieberstein, Samuel, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Liebich, Andre, 1982-1997 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Lin, Yu-sheng, 1964-1970 (Box 4, Folder 10-A)
    - Lincoln, Bruce, 1965-1980 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Loe, Mary Louise, 1970-1987 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Longley, David, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Lubasz, Herinz, 1960-1988 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - McKitrick, Eric, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - McLean, Hugh, 1960-1979 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - MacNaughton, Ruth, 1970-1974 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Macey, David, 1970-1985 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Malia, Martin, 1964-1972 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      (See also correspondence of 1959-1961 Series III: Menshevik project--Subseries III.1: Project records--Sub-subseries III.1.1: Correspondence--Advisory Committee, Box 14, Folder 8-9)
    - Mandel, James, 1971-1976 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Mandel, Mark, 1972-1986 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Manning, Roberta, 1969-1993 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Mayer, Daniel, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      (Societe des Amis de Leon Blum)
    - Mazelis, Jack, 1966-1972 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Mead, Margaret, 1964, 1977, (included photographs) (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Medlin, Virgil Dewain, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Meisner, Maurice, 1960-1977 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Menashe, Louis, 1968-1984 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Miletijevic, Radmila, 1963-1975 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Miller, Burton, 1984-1993 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Miller, Martin, 1966-1972 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Mixter, Timothy, 1986-1988 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Monas, Sidney, 1959-1987 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Monde, 1980-1982 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Montgomery, David, 1972-1982 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Moore, Barrington, 1970, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Mosely, Philip, 1959-1972 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      (See also Mosely-Dallin correspondence of 1964-1965 in: Dallin, Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Moskowitz, David, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Neal, James, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Nelson, Mary: see Fisch, Mary
    - New York Times, 1963-1964, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      (letter of 1963-1964 signed by Haimson and Marc Raeff)
    - O'Brien, Mildred, 1971-1975 (Box 6, Folder 4-7)
    - Parsons, Steven, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Petrusha, Ronald, 1977-1983 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Phillips, George, 1960-1975 (Box 6, Folder 9-10)
    - Pintner, Walter, 1970-1972, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 11)